Under the blue sky
Outside in the feathery grass by the river
Let's play hide-and-seek
A patch of sunflowers
Let's blow, blow round bubbles
What shall I do?
Even the obvious things are always so hard
I just want to grin when I'm happy, sing when I'm in love
They say my dreams will come true someday
but when will someday come? I can't wait!
Count one, two, three and spread my arms
Gather the light to myself
Where is it? Tell me what I can do
Even if I'm hurt so much, even if I run so hard
Even if I collapse crying over and over, I still
believe in my amazing future
Chase the white, white clouds.
... An organ, and boyhood days.
There!
space
Run, run! Run, run! Along with our friends!
It's too goddamn hot for anyone to be that enthusiastic in the morning.
What's that song, anyway?
I learned it from the kids at the nursery.
It's a fun song, don't you think?
On top of the mountain-
That scared me!
I thought I was gonna fall.
Shut up!
Good morning!
What are you doing up this early on a Sunday?
I'm airing out my mattress!
It's great weather for it, isn't it?
Oh man. Can't you take anything easy?
Meanie.
Dobato!
Ioryogi! Are you okay?
Am I okay!?
I told you! I'm supposed to be a stuffed animal out here! Quit doing this kind of thing to me!
Sorry!
All right, I'm leaving.
Take care.
Okay.
Chitose must be seeing Fujimoto off.
Looks that way.
That's weird.
Why?
He was just in the next room. And now he's gone.
He's always so busy.
Wait, maybe...
Maybe there's two Fujimotos!
No way! That's like something out of a suspense drama.
Kobato! What was that?
It was nothing!
Where are you going?
Yomogi Nursery.
Don't you have today off?
The weather's so nice that I thought I'd air out the mattresses.
Hey, Kobato. Don't you get it?
Get what?
Why did you come here?
To fill that bottle with candy!
Okay, if you get that, don't you think you have better things to do on your Sunday off?
But...
I want to help out at Yomogi, even if it's not much.
Here's the report.  The previous headmaster of Yomogi Nursery got conned into borrowing a lot of money.
The previous headmaster?
Yes.  Okiura Sayaka's father.  He died two years ago.
The guys who did it are a pretty tough bunch, but one of them has some connections with Sayaka.
Miss Sayaka.
Kobato?
What's up? You have today off.
I thought I'd air out the mattresses.
The mattresses?
Yeah! The weather's great for it.
Wow, it really is nice out.
I didn't even notice.
Hey, let's air them out together.
Okay!
Chitose was so happy to have a nice girl like you move in.
I'm having a lot of fun living with Chitose, Chiho and Chise, too.
How about Fujimoto?
Is he being mean to you again?
Sometimes he is, but sometimes he isn't.
I don't really get it. What kind of person is he?
He's kinder than he looks.
He was that way when he was little, too.
A little Fujimoto? I can't even imagine it.
Do you want to see?
Sorry to keep you waiting. I found it.
Here.
Wow, he's so tiny!
Is this really Fujimoto?
Yes.
It's a picture of the first day he came here.
Fujimoto came to Yomogi?
No, that's not it.
Fujimoto was an orphan.
Orphan? What's an orphan?
A child with no mommy or daddy, no family.
You shouldn't even start if you're not ready to commit to taking care of it.
If you're just going to take things halfway so you can be self-satisfied,
you're as bad as the guy who abandoned her to begin with.
So...
That's why he said that...
Kobato?
Tell me!
I want to know all about little Fujimoto!
Okay.
It must have been 14 years ago...
My father took Fujimoto in.
I'm home, Sayaka.
This is the boy I've been talking about. His name is Fujimoto Kiyokazu.
Kiyokazu, this is my daughter Sayaka.
I'm Sayaka. Nice to meet you, Kiyokazu.
I know! Let's take a picture to remember this by!
I'll go get the camera.
Camera, where's the camera...
Here goes.
On the gi in Yomogi!
Fujimoto lived here from that day on.
He looks angry here.
Yeah. He always looked like that when he first came.
He didn't open up to anyone.
Not even you, Miss Sayaka?
Yeah. He was always alone...
We tried introducing him to the other kids.
Everyone was interested at first,
but he never played with them,
so he just drew further away.
He didn't seem to have any friends at school either.
Fujimoto himself seemed like he didn't want to get along with anyone,
so we started to think we couldn't do anything about it.
Welcome back!
You've gotta say "I'm back!"
I hate you, Kiyokazu.
Me too.
Bye-bye, Sayaka!
Bye-bye! See you tomorrow!
Kiyokazu, do you like the organ?
Kiyokazu?
Sayaka!
Bye-bye! See you tomorrow!
Fujimoto...
Tasty cold beer!
We're giving them out free!
Can I get one?
Here you go!
Would you like a tasty beer?
We're promoting them.
Excuse me.
Can I have one?
Yes. It's a new brand. Give it a try.
Thanks!
Shuichiro will be so happy to have one!
It was on a nice summer day like this.
My turn next!
No, it's my turn!
You just went!
Stop fighting and wait your turn.
Okay!
Will they bloom soon?
You've all worked so hard. I'm sure they'll be beautiful.
Really?
Really!
All right!
Now let's clean up, and then we can play.
Okay!
Welcome back.
Tomo, are you okay?
The ball came flying, and Tomo was so surprised she fell over.
Where does it hurt? Are you okay?
Ow!
Why'd ya shove me?
Sorry, sorry.
I didn't think you'd really fall.
Don't give me that! I'm a mess now!
Come on, let's just find the ball!
You're the one who missed the pass.
Fine.
Man, I can't get it off.
How'd it get this wet here?
Hold it!
Just what are you two doing?
Well, uh, our ball got loose, so...
That's dangerous! You could have hit her!
We didn't, so why are you angry?
Get out of the garden!
We all worked so hard taking care of these sunflowers.
Everyone was so happy that they were about to bloom!
Here's your ball.
You need to apologize to the kids before you leave, too!
My bad.
Sorry.
You and your big trap.
Then don't go there!
Sayaka...
The sunflowers!
Don't worry, they're just a little hurt.
If we hold them up like this,
and water them every day, I'm sure they'll be fine.
Really?
Chase the white, white, clouds
Run, run! Along with our friends
On top of the mountain, we can see everything
Let's look, look for new mysteries!
You know how many jobs Fujimoto has, right?
Yeah.
He's a pizza boy, and a bike messenger, and he delivers newspapers. A lot of other things too.
That many?
Yeah.
He's working hard to pay down the nursery's debt.
For the nursery?
Yes. And... to become a lawyer.
He's up so late every night studying.
I'm worried he'll wear himself out.
It's so soft and smells so good.
It smells like sunshine.
Like sunshine?
Yeah. When you air mattresses out, they smell like sunshine.
That's what my father told me.
Tomorrow, let's let them all nap in the sunshine.
Yeah.
What's so funny?
Nothing. It sounds worderful.
Yeah. I'm looking forward to it!
Anyway, let's take them in.
Yeah!
Thanks for coming in today. Take care.
Okay. See you tomorrow.
Sunshine, huh...
It's Kiyokazu!
Welcome back!
Are you going to play the organ?
Play it! Play it!
It's Kiyokazu!
Yeah!
Welcome back!
Welcome back.
I...
I'm back.
C'mon, Kiyokazu, play the organ!
Hurry! Hurry!
I see a red, red sunset
Let's walk, walk on
If it's sunny tomorrow, let's come and play
Let's go home, let's go home, my house is right there.
C'mon, look! You're not getting anything!
But I just wanted to air out the mattresses.
I just wanted to help out at the nursery.
Never mind the mattresses, you're hanging me out to dry here!
Sorry!
Kobato? Ioryogi?
I knew it was you.
Great. I thought I'd give you this.
Can I?
Shuichiro has plenty in the fridge.
Then I'll go right ahead!
Isn't that nice, Ioryogi?
All right, here goes!
No, wait, I should save it to enjoy right before bed.
Kohaku, you're always so serious about taking care of the trees in the garden.
It's all I can do for Shuichiro.
I'm just happy I can at least do this.
I'm so happy I can help out at Yomogi, too.
Yeah! Being able to help people that are important to you is such a happy thing.
Important people?
Yomogi Nursery must be really important to Fujimoto.
Yeah. Otherwise he wouldn't work so many jobs.
It's the same.
Me too.
Yomogi Nursery is really important to me too.
I want to work hard and help out Miss Sayaka and everyone.
I'll try my best!
You're doing it wrong again.
Welcome home, Kobato.
Welcome!
Welcome back!
I'm back.
Fujimoto! You were so cute as a little boy!
Didn't you used to get so into playing the organ when you were little,
tapping away with your feet on the pedals?
How'd you know that?
Miss Sayaka showed me a picture today.
I wanna see!
Me too!
I want to see little Kiyokazu too.
Even Chitose!?
For someone who used to be so cute, you sure get angry a lot.
Quit talking about it!
But we wanna hear!
What shall we do?
I know, we'll wait until he's gone!
People all want to fly
but they're cheated by gravity
everyone can really fly
She must be so unhappy because
she forgot her own shadow somewhere
Then...
If you tell me "thanks", if you say "thanks" and smile
Going back and forth, we'll be happy
You'll be happy, there'll be nothing to worry about
As long as we're together
It's strange, I'm crying even though I'm happy
... Detective Hanato Kobato.
Next episode